Association on American Indian Affairs Records, 1851-2016 (bulk 1922-1995): Finding Aid MC147
Public Policy Papers
- Series 2: Subject Files, 1851-1995; 332 boxes
  - Subseries 1: General, 1868-1995; 116 boxes
    The interest taken by the AAIA in other entities concerned with Native Americans -- be they Indian or non-Indian in composition -- is also documented in this subseries. Particularly well-represented are the American Indian Development Corporation, the American Indian Policy Review Commission, the Association of Contract Tribal Schools, the National Congress of American Indians, the National Indian Education Association, and the Organization for Social and Technical Innovation. There are files which contain only informational material and, thus, suggest a minimum of interaction, as in the case of the American Indian Archaeological Institute, and there are files which reveal a collaborative spirit, as in the case of the Native American Rights Fund. Cordiality as well as hostility can be found. The American Indian Press Association, which the AAIA lauded as serving "an extremely useful and much needed function," is illustrative of the former, while the American Indian Federation, with its Nazi proclivities, -- "a notoriously disreputable group," in La Farge's words -- falls squarely in the latter camp. While the AAIA offered support to organizations such as the American Indian Nurses Association, it sought assistance from charitable institutions such as the John Hay Whitney Foundation. Indeed, the significant number of philanthropic bodies contained in this subseries underscores the financial pressures experienced by the Association as it sought to mount a diversified and effective program. Governmental bodies are also well-represented, either in their own right or in files addressing specific issues. Not unexpectedly, material relating to the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior predominates: evidence of the pervasive role its programs and personnel have played in Native American life. Of particular interest are files relating to the Association's vexed relationship with Commissioners of Indian Affairs Dillon Myer and Glenn Emmons in the 1950s, both of whom espoused the speedy termination of federal responsibilities for Native Americans.
    Rounding out this subseries are sometimes substantial files on the issues which engaged the attention and consumed the energies of the AAIA. While the files in this category hold evidence of concrete action, they also contain the accumulation of data on which the Association based its policies. A fluid picture emerges as the rejuvenation of Indian arts and crafts or the struggle to halt the termination of recognized tribes gives way to the preservation of Indian families or the struggle to secure the acknowledgement of unrecognized tribes. Issues such as health and education loomed large from one decade to the next, even if the focus shifted, for example, from trachoma to acquired immune deficiency syndrome. Still other matters, such as the occupation of the Bureau of Indian Affairs' headquarters by the American Indian Movement in 1972, flared up and died down suddenly, baring old antagonisms. Taken as a whole, this subseries sheds a revealing light on the AAIA, the players who shared its stage, and the dramas -- sometimes resolved and sometimes not -- in which it acted. It also demonstrates that over the years this stage has grown ever more crowded and ever more Indian in representation, though the challenges confronting Native Americans have not thereby abated.
    The materials in this subseries are arranged alphabetically by name of individual, corporate body or issue.
    - "The AAIA: Four Decades of Indian History", 1962; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - A and S Tribal Industries, 1985; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Aaron E. Norman Fund, 1957-1966; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Aboriginal Public Policy Institute, 1990-1991; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Acorn Foundation Trust, 1963; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS), 1987-1994; 3 folders (Box 57, Folder 6-8)
    - Ad-Net, 1991-1992; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Advance, 1954; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Advisory Committee on Indian Affairs, 1959-1962; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, 1993; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians, 1955-1989; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Agricultural Extension Services, 1955-1961; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Agriculture, 1975-1988; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - AKC Fund, 1962-1963; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Alan Guttmacher Institute, 1993; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - Alcohol and Drug Abuse, 1916-1976; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - Alcohol and Drug Abuse, 1977-1992; 2 folders (Box 58, Folder 1-2)
    - Alliance of Native Americans, 1988; 1 folder (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Alovis, Barbara, 1973-1975; 1 folder (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Amazon Network, 1993; 1 folder (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - American Academy of Child Psychiatry, 1973-1985; 2 folders (Box 58, Folder 6-7)
    - American Anthropological Association, 1984-1985; 1 folder (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1988; 1 folder (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1932-1976; 1 folder (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlet on Indian Reorganization Act, 1938-1939; 1 folder (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - American Freedom From Hunger Foundation, 1971-1974; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - American Heritage Foundation, 1958-1964; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - American Indian/Alaskan Native Nurses Association, 1979-1982; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - American Indian Archaeological Institute, undated; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - American Indian Businessmen's Association, 1974; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - American Indian Charter Convention, 1960-1962; 2 folders (Box 59, Folder 6-7)
    - American Indian College Fund, 1990-1993; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - American Indian Dance Theatre, 1987-1988; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - American Indian Defense Association, 1923-1937; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - American Indian Development Corporation, 1980; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - American Indian Development Corporation, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
    - American Indian Development Finance Institute Planning Conference, 1980; 2 folders (Box 60, Folder 3-4)
    - American Indian Federation, 1937-1939; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - American Indian Forestry Association, 1978; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - American Indian Graduate Student Association, 1978-1983; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - American Indian Law Clinic, 1992; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - American Indian Law Students Association, 1979; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - American Indian Law Symposium, 1986; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - American Indian Lawyer Training Program, 1974-1980; 1987; 2 folders (Box 60, Folder 11-12)
    - American Indian Lawyers Association, 1972; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - American Indian Memorials, 1955-1992; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - American Indian Movement, 1974-1977; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - American Indian National Bank, 1979-1984; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - American Indian Nurses Association, 1973-1977; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - American Indian Policy Review Commission, 1975-1976; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - American Indian Policy Review Commission Report, 1977; 2 folders (Box 61, Folder 5-6)
    - American Indian Policy Review Commission Report, 1977; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - American Indian Press Association, 1971-1975; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - American Indian Ritual Object Repatriation Foundation, 1992-1993; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - American Indian Science and Engineering Society, 1981-1993; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - American Indian Scouting Outreach, 1976-1981; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - American Indian Society of Creative Arts, 1961; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - American Indian Technical Services, 1987; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - American Indian Women's Service League, 1960; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - American Indians -- United, 1968-1969; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - American Institute of Architects, 1966-1970; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Americans for Children's Relief, 1971-1972; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Americans for Indian Opportunity, 1970-1992; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Amnesty International, 1992; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Amory, Cleveland, 1961-1964; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Anderson, Arnold T, 1976-1983; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Anderson, Frank R, 1963-1964; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Anderson, Owanah, 1985-1993; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Anderson/Lucey Presidential Campaign, 1980; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Angelita's Fund, 1973; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Anti-Indian Sentiment, 1977; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Appointment Calendar, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Arizona State University Indian Education Program, undated; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Arrows in the Dust (Columbia Broadcasting System), 1948; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Articles, 1918-1927; 1938-1953; 2 folders (Box 63, Folder 13-14)
    - Articles, 1954-1968; 1970-1979; 1981-1994; 4 folders (Box 64, Folder 1-4)
    - Articles: La Farge, Oliver, 1934-1960; 1 folder (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Artists Space, 1986-1987; 1 folder (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Arts and Crafts, 1915-1934; 1 folder (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Arts and Crafts, 1934-1945; 1951-1994; 4 folders (Box 65, Folder 1-4)
    - Arts and Crafts Resource Guide, 1988-1989; 1 folder (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Associated Indigenous Communications, 1986; 1 folder (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Association of American Indian Physicians, 1975-1987; 1 folder (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Association of Contract Tribal Schools, 1979-1982; 1 folder (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Association of Contract Tribal Schools, 1983-1986; 2 folders (Box 66, Folder 1-2)
    - Association of Native American Health Professionals, 1973-1974; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - ATLATL, 1978-1981; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Attorney Contracts With Tribes, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Aurora Foundation, 1986-1987; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Australia: Aboriginal Child Welfare, 1975-1978; 2 folders (Box 66, Folder 7-8)
    - Australia: Aboriginal Child Welfare, 1979-1985; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Australia: Aboriginal Land Rights, 1974-1979; 2 folders (Box 67, Folder 2-3)
    - Australia: Aboriginal Law Centre, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Australia: Kimberley Land Council, 1980; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Australia: Law Reform Commission, 1977-1982; 2 folders (Box 67, Folder 6-7)
    - Australia: National Aboriginal Education Committee, 1978; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Australia: Publications, 1972-1980; undated; 2 folders (Box 68, Folder 1-2)
    - Australia: Queensland Aboriginal Legislation, 1971-1979; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Australia: Tomlinson, John, 1980; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Australia: Trade Union Committee on Aboriginal Rights, 1979; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Australia: Uranium, 1976-1980; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Australia: General, 1975-1984; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Avalon Foundation, 1952-1953; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Avon Glove Corporation, 1984; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - B. de Rothschild Foundation for the Arts and Sciences, 1955-1958; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Bad Hand, Howard P, 1972-1976; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Baer, Linda L, 1986; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Bahti, Tom, 1969-1972; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Baker, John E., Sr, 1969-1972; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Ban the Dam Jam, 1991; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Banbury Fund, 1984-1985; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Barbara Warden Foundation, 1963; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Barker Welfare Foundation, 1948-1953; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Barksdale Foundation, 1962; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Barrett, Janet, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - Basso, Keith H, 1978-1993; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 21)
    - Battelle Memorial Institute, 1992; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Bauer, Gary, 1987; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Baumgartner, Leona, 1962-1980; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Beardsley, Helen M, 1971; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Becker, Edward J, 1949; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Beddall, Thomas H., Jr, 1969-1978; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Bell, Griffin B, 1979; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Ben-Ami, Henri, 1965; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Benefit Performance of Indians, 1969; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Bennett, Robert L, 1966-1969; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Bergen, Alfreda Janis, 1966-1987; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Better Business Bureaus, 1944-1994; 2 folders (Box 69, Folder 12-13)
    - Bibb Company, 1972-1977; 2 folders (Box 70, Folder 1-2)
    - Bibliographies, 1939-1992; undated; 2 folders (Box 70, Folder 3-4)
    - Big Bear Spiritual Run, 1988; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Bigart, Homer, 1970-1971; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Birchfield, J. Kermit, Jr, 1982-1986; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Bison, 1989; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Black, Algernon D, 1955; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Black, Charles L., Jr, 1950-1965; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Black Hills Sioux Nation Council, 1954; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Black War Veterans of the United States Association, 1993; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Blackbird, Edith, 1954-1961; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Blackwolf, Charles, 1953; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Blanchard, Evelyn Lance, 1977-1993; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Blatchford, Herb, 1969-1976; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Blue Hill Foundation, 1954-1960; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Board for Fundamental Education, 1958; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Boarding Schools, 1868-1894; 1924-1939; 1948-1970; 1972-1979; 6 folders (Box 71, Folder 5-10)
    - Boarding Schools, 1980-1986; undated; 3 folders (Box 72, Folder 1-3)
    - Bobelu, Carolyn, 1985-1987; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Bolivian Textiles, 1990; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Borbridge, John, Jr, 1970; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Borg-Marks and Payne Company, 1988; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Botelho, Eugene, 1960; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Bowler, Alida C, 1947-1958; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Boy Scouts of America, 1960; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Brackish Groundwater, 1965-1978; 2 folders (Box 72, Folder 11-12)
    - Bradford, Penelope S, 1974-1985; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Brady, Steven C., Sr, 1990; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Brando, Marlon, Sr, 1963-1964; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Brennan, Jere, 1975; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Broadcasting, 1988-1993; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Broden, Leo, 1966-1974; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Broken Arrow (20th Century Fox), 1949-1956; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Bronson, Ruth Muskrat, 1951-1963; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Brookings Institution, 1956; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Brophy, William A, 1945-1962; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Brown, Ivan, 1969-1972; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Brown, Oscar Deric, undated; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Brown Thunder, Joseph, Jr, 1992; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Bruner, Edward M, 1952-1955; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Buder, Kathryn M, 1988-1993; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Aberdeen Area Office, 1958; 1985-1987; 2 folders (Box 73, Folder 15-16)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Bill of Particulars Against, 1952; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Conferences, 1939; 1966; 2 folders (Box 73, Folder 18-19)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Credit Program, 1954; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Directory of Field and Central Offices, 1962; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Directory of Field Offices, 1990; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 22)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Economic Development Initiative, 1982; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 23)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Education Report, 1988; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 24)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Employment and Volunteering, 1979-1982; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 25)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: General Assistance Program, 1972; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 26)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: History, 1957; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 27)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Indian Industrial Development Program, 1962; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 28)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Indian Involvement Program, 1971; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Information Service, 1951-1953; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Job Placement Program, 1949-1951; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Occupation of Headquarters, 1972-1973; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Personnel, 1941-1962; 1991; 2 folders (Box 74, Folder 5-6)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Policy Matters, 1953-1963; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Reorganization, 1923; 1931-1954; 1960-1983; 3 folders (Box 74, Folder 8-10)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Scholarship Program, 1973-1974; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: Window Rock Area Office, 1951-1954; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs: General, 1930-1938; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Burge, Moris, 1939; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Burke, Charles H, 1925-1929; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Burnette, Robert Philip, 1963; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Bush Administration, 1991-1992; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Byler, Mary Lou, 1972-1973; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Byler, William, 1962; 1979-1986; 2 folders (Box 74, Folder 19-20)
    - Campbell, Ben Nighthorse, 1987-1993; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - Canada, 1946-1963; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Canada, 1971-1993; 2 folders (Box 75, Folder 1-2)
    - Canadian Indian Child Welfare, 1973-1984; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Cannon, Bruce K, 1990-1991; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Carlos, Filmore, 1968-1975; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1952-1986; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Carter/Mondale Presidential Campaign, 1976; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Carver, John A., Jr, 1961-1962; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Cassadore, Marlowe, 1986-1987; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Catano, Yolima, 1987; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Cazenovia College, 1986-1987; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Census, 1971-1974; 1980-1987; 2 folders (Box 75, Folder 12-13)
    - Census, 1987-1992; 2 folders (Box 76, Folder 1-2)
    - Center for Life Cycle Sciences, 1990-1993; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Charles A. Frueauff Foundation, 1952-1960; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Charles and Lily H. Weinberg Foundation, 1957; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Charles Luckman Associates, 1971-1976; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Chavers, Dean, 1987; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Chestnut, Peter C, 1968-1970; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Child Abuse, 1966-1975; 2 folders (Box 76, Folder 9-10)
    - Child Abuse, 1976-1991; undated; 4 folders (Box 77, Folder 1-4)
    - Child Abuse Survey, 1986; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Child Welfare, 1960; 1968-1972; 3 folders (Box 77, Folder 6-8)
    - Child Welfare, 1973-1975; 5 folders (Box 78, Folder 1-5)
    - Child Welfare, 1976-1991; 5 folders (Box 79, Folder 1-5)
    - Child Welfare, undated; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Child Welfare and Reasonable Efforts, 1984-1987; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Child Welfare Book, 1976-1989; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Child Welfare Crisis, 1972; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Child Welfare League of America, 1968-1977; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Child Welfare Resource People, 1972-1976; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Child Welfare State-of-the-Field Study, 1976; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Child Welfare Statistics: AAIA, 1966-1978; undated; 2 folders (Box 81, Folder 1-2)
    - Child Welfare Statistics: Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1967-1987; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Children's Bureau, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Christian Century, 1954-1959; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Christopher Columbus Quincentenary, 1989-1992; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Churches, 1950-1956; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Churchman, 1954; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Civil Rights, 1950-1988; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Claflen, George L., Jr, 1982-1985; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Claflin, Charlotte Isabel, 1961-1964; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Clapp, Winifred I, 1957-1964; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Clark, Ella E, 1954-1991; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Clergy League for America, 1938-1939; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Clifford, John, 1976-1980; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Clinton/Gore Presidential Campaign, 1992; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Coal Slurry Pipelines, 1977-1983; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Coalition for American Indian Justice of the Riverside Church, 1984-1986; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Coalition of Eastern Native Americans, 1973-1976; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Coalition of Indian Controlled School Boards, 1971-1985; 2 folders (Box 82, Folder 11-12)
    - Cohen, Felix S, 1945-1954; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Cohen, Lucy Kramer, 1954-1993; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - Colcord, Charles E, 1980; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - Coleman, Nancy R, 1935-1939; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - College Board, 1986-1987; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - Collier, John, 1933-1934; 1944-1962; 2 folders (Box 83, Folder 1-2)
    - Colorado, Pamela Kiser, 1975-1981; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Columbia University, 1953-1969; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Commissioner of Indian Affairs Appointment, 1932-1933; 1950; 1952-1953; 4 folders (Box 83, Folder 5-8)
    - Committee on Indian Affairs Report to Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government, 1948; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs, U.S. House of Representatives, 1957; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Commonwealth Fund, 1951-1957; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Community Chests and Councils of America, 1954; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Community Funds, 1973-1976; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Community Health Representatives, 1972; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Community Leaders Conference on Tuberculosis and Health, 1969; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - "A Comprehensive Evaluation of Office of Economic Opportunity Community Action Programs on Six Selected Indian Reservations", 1966; 2 folders (Box 84, Folder 1-2)
    - Conference of Friends of the American Indian, 1938; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Conference on Wildlife, Recreation and Related Resource Problems, 1947; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Congressional Coalition on Adoption, 1985; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Congressional Investigation into Un-American Activities, 1958; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 6)